下午好 感谢各位大驾光临
Good afternoon. Thanks for coming.
能在大家的笑容映衬下度过生日
It's so nice to spend my birthday
我实在倍感荣幸
surrounded by so many smiling faces.
其实今天我本来郁闷得不想来了
I was almost too depressed to come today.
因为我刚意识到我虚度了我的童年
I realized I let my childhood slip away.
各位快行动起来
Come on, everybody!
曼尼的生日会要迟到了
We're gonna be late for Manny's birthday!
快走 快走 快走 快走 快走
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
我这就能走 妈
I'm ready, mom.
-宝贝 你确定吗 -没错
- You sure, honey? - Yep.
那你看下自己的脚
Then take a quick peek at your feet.
卢克 你不给力啊
Oh! Come on, Luke!
您老是要亲自走快点儿呢
Are you gonna walk faster,
还是让我去车里拿莉莉的婴儿车推您走
or should I get Lily's stroller out of the car and push you?
你急什么啊
Would you relax?
那餐馆离这儿也就5分钟
The restaurant's like five minutes away from here
免费润肤露耶
Ohh, free lotion.
别走走停停的了 咱还没给曼尼买礼物呢
Stop Stopping to smell the roses. Manny's present.
你可真是典型的普里契特家的人
Ohh, you are such a Pritchett.
你这是啥意思
What's that supposed to mean?
快走 快走 快走 快走 快走
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
我在找钥匙
I'm looking for the keys!
你总是有理
Of course you are.
我这人一向准时
I like being on time.
这不难做到 因为我有条不紊
It's easy 'cause I'm organized.
我老婆则不然
Not my wife.
按理说在满是行刑队
You'd think growing up in a place
和老酒鬼的国度中长大
full of death squads and drunken uncles,
她做事本该利索点才对
she'd have learned to move a little bit faster.
对不起 对不起
Sorry, sorry.
我刚刚找耳环去了
I couldn't find my earring.
我们说到哪儿啦
So, what were we talking about, huh?
亲爱的 快点儿 我们要迟到了 走吧
Honey, come on. We're gonna be late. Let's go.
好好好 等我填完家庭夏令营申请表就走
Yeah, yeah, just filling out the application to family camp.
你总不能上次赢了热舞比赛
You don't win the "dirty dancing" competition
而这次却不去捍卫你的冠军宝座吧
and not go back to defend your crown.
你说得对 快走吧 亲爱的
That's right. Come on, honey.
不过想要争冠军
But shoot for the king...
除非把冠军干掉
you better kill him.
每年夏天 我们都去参加一周家庭夏令营
Every summer, we spend a week at family camp.
和普通夏令营没差别 不过要全家出动
It's just like regular camp, but with the family!
这还用解释吗 菲尔
I don't think that needed any clarification, Phil.
某人去年输了彩弹大战
Somebody's still a little touchy
-到现在还耿耿于怀呢 -才没有
- about losing last year's color war. - Not.
她是蓝队
She was on team blue...
...我管他们叫"傻队"[谐音"loser"输家]
...or as I like to refer to them as team blue-zer.
-我是白队 -别说了
- And I was on white. - That's good.
-不是白队... -不要说了
- And if you ain't white... - No.
...只能败北
...you ain't right!
菲尔 你怎么还不长记性呢
Phil! Have you learned nothing?
谢啦 伙计
My good man.
好了 同志们快点 给我在前门集合
Okay, come on, everybody. Front door! Now!
克莱尔 别着急 也就十五分钟路程
Claire, relax. It takes 15 minutes to get there.
要二十分钟
It takes 20 minutes.
那是你的路线
If we take your route.
我的路线最直接了
Well, my way is the most direct.
我看是直接堵车了
Directly into traffic.
你的路线直接就是 最烂的那条
Uh, your way is directly into...the suckiest way.
想来点有趣的吗
Want to make this interesting?
我不认为这件事能有趣
Yeah, I don't think that's possible.
咱们一人一辆车 比谁先开到
We take two cars and see who gets there first.
好啊 比就比 现在就比
Fine. Fine. Let's do that. It's on.
太好了 比赛开始
Yeah! It is on!
姑娘们跟我走
I'll take the girls.
卢克 你爸和我要分开
Luke, your dad and I are splitting up.
-为啥啊 -又因为傻事吵架了呗
- Why? - Another one of their stupid arguments.
那好 我要跟老爸
Okay. I'll go with dad.
不不 伙计 跟我走
No, no. Buddy. Come with me.
咱们这就 没穿鞋
Prepare to be -- my shoes.
菲尔 你不给力啊
Come on, Phil!
我看起来咋样
How do I look?
像艾尔·卡彭[美国史上著名黑帮老大]
Like Al Capone.
谢啦
Thanks!
生日快乐 孩子
Happy birthday, kid.
气枪吗
A BB gun?!
好好玩吧 这是当年我爸给我最好的礼物
Enjoy. That's the best gift my dad ever gave me.
我死活找不到钥匙
My keys are nowhere!
我们只能开你的车了
We're gonna have to go in your car.
我的车还在店里
It's in the shop.
你还记得最后一次把钥匙放哪了吗
Where was the last place you put your keys?
这又成我的错啦
Oh, so now it's my fault?
应该是你最后一次把钥匙放哪儿了
Where was the last place you put my keys?
买车的时候放你手里了
In your hand when I bought you the car.
杰 包装盒上写着
Hey, Jay, on the box,
"适合十六岁及以上儿童"
it says "Ages 16 and up."
这礼物适合我吗
Is this an appropriate gift for me?
你开啥玩笑 你生来就十六岁了
Are you kidding me? You were born 16.
你知道吗 要是你没弄丢备用钥匙
You know, we wouldn't be having this problem
咱们现在也不至于这样
if you hadn't lost the spare set.
我才没弄丢呢
I didn't lose them.
是有人进来偷走的
Somebody came in here and stole them!
光偷钥匙不偷车吗
And left the car.
什么叫我生来就十六岁
What do you mean, I was born 16?
我只是说 你一直不像个小孩儿
I'm just saying, you were never much of a kid.
这是好事呀 因为我从来不喜欢小孩儿
And that's a good thing, 'cause I never liked kids.
你不如去冰箱那儿找找
You know, you ought to try the fridge.
上次你就把手机丢那儿了
'Cause that's where we found your cellphone.
就那么一次 杰
It was only one time, Jay.
你知道我一跟我妈打完电话 就想吃东西
And you know I always eat after I talk to my mother.
生日快乐 老伙计
Happy birthday, old man.
我的人生已经错过了太多精彩
Well, I've forgotten a lot of things in my life.
杰的一番话简直是醍醐灌顶
But what Jay said hit me hard.
我错过了我的童年
I'd forgotten to have a childhood.
老爹 你刚刚闯红灯了
Dad, that was a stop sign.
回家的时候我停两次就行了
I'll stop twice on the way back.
很好 我们终于有机会拿回
Oh, good, it'll give us a chance to pick up that hubcap
你横穿教堂停车场时落下的轮圈了
you lost cutting through the temple parking lot.
黄灯 黄灯
Yellow...yellow!
好吧
Okay.
看到没
Are you seeing this?
一路绿灯 咱都不用开多快
We are making every light, and we don't even have to speed.
还是我的路给力
The system works.
老妈
Mom?
我知道 我刚刚是有点超速了
I know, I went a little fast back there,
不过说真的 四十跟三十五差不多
but, really, 40 is the same as 35.
你老这么说[讽刺年龄]
You say that a lot.
我觉得你们还不知道现在该担心什么
I don't think you two appreciate what's at stake here.
-我们的命吗 -你们知道我爱你们妈妈
- Our lives? - You know I love your mother,
但你们也知道她那副嘴脸
but I think you also know a certain look she gets
那种"听我的 我永远是对的"的表情
That says, "Just listen to me, I'm always right".
你是说她盛气凌人的表情吗
You mean her face?
现在你懂我的意思了吧
N-now we're getting this.
如果我们这次赢了
If we're right this one time,
以后就不用再听她指使了
then we never have to be right again.
当她说"那气球载不了人的 菲尔"
When she says, "That balloon can't carry a person, Phil",
我就说"记得曼尼生日那次吗"
I say, "Manny's birthday".
"穿上夹克 艾丽克斯 会下雨的"
"Take your jacket, Alex. I think it's gonna rain".
"记得曼尼生日那次吗"
"Manny's birthday".
别看我 看路
Don't look at me. Look at the road.
"记得曼尼生日那次吗"
"Manny's birthday".
不 老爸 看路 前面有卡车
No, dad! Look at the road! There's a truck!
没长眼睛吗 混蛋
Sweet baby! Assholes!
你老爸这次输惨了
We are so kicking your dad's butt!
我们是最棒的
We are the best ones!
你和爸爸为什么要分手呀
How come you and dad are breaking up?
什么
What?
如果只是一点意见不合的话
If it's just a little disagreement,
你们就不能好好解决吗
can't you just work it out?
亲爱的 你以为
Oh, sweetie, you thought
我说我们要分开的时候是指
that when I said we were splitting up...
不 不 我跟你爸好着呢 宝贝儿
No. No, your dad and I are fine, honey.
我们只是要一人开一辆车
We just were gonna take separate cars
看谁先到餐厅
to see who could get to the restaurant faster.
那我就放心了
Oh, that's a relief.
你刚才肯定难受死了
Ohh, you must have been feeling awful back there.
我真抱歉
I am so sorry.
没事的
It's okay.
你刚才为什么说你要跟你爸走
Why did you say you'd go with your dad?
太好了 这下老妈又要赢了
Great. Mom gets to be right again.
这种态度可是会输掉的
Hey, bad attitudes lose races.
不对 冲向路边然后爆胎才会输呢
No, swerving into a curb and popping your tire loses races.
我们应该报警说妈妈的车是偷来的
We should call the cops and say mom's car was stolen.
然后警察就会去抓她 我们就赢了
They arrest her, we win.
不行 警察会追踪报警电话的
No, they trace those calls.
但是精神可嘉 开始有团队思考意识了
But this is great. Thinking like a team!
这对我们的家庭露营会有帮助的
Good practice for family camp.
我们 我们今年还要去吗
We're, uh, we're doing that again?
而且今年我有预感 白队会大获全胜
And this year I predict total white domination.
受不了那鬼地方了
Can't go back there.
我听说今年夏天要跳风土舞
I heard this summer there's gonna be a hoedown.
我受不了了
I can't.
海莉
Haley!
我受不了了 受不了了
I can't! I can't.
跟文具店的女售货员聊了八分钟
Eight minutes talking to the lady at the stationery store
结果还是什么礼物都没买到
and still no present.
我认为新朋友就像礼物一样
You know, I think a new friend is like a present.
是啊是啊 我也读过那张卡片了
Yeah, I read that card, too.
我们能不能买我们看好的下一个东西
Can we please just buy the next thing we see
然后赶紧走啊
and get out of here?
你为什么就不能享受一下这个过程呢
You know, why can't you enjoy this?
今天下午天气那么好 莉莉托给保姆了
It's a beautiful afternoon, Lily's with a sitter.
这是咱俩的二人世界
The day is ours!
海伦
Helen!
Helen!!
看呀 又交了个朋友 走吧 忙着呢
Oh, look at that. Another friend. Off we go. Very busy.
不要 站住
No. Stop.
你太受你那些死板的计划束缚了
You are too tied to your rigid schedules.
你错过了真正的生活
You're missing life.
你只要花两秒钟就可以帮到这个人
It took all of two seconds to help this nice man.
等 等等 我还没说完呢
W-w-wait. Wait. There's more.
两秒钟而已 还要说什么
Two seconds. Yeah.
告诉她我很抱歉 我一直爱着她
Tell her I'm so sorry, I've always loved her.
他说他很抱歉
He says he's so sorry!
他一直爱着你
And that he's always loved you!
请上来跟我谈谈
Please come up and talk to me.
请上来跟他谈谈
Please come up and talk to him!
你走了 他的生活将暗淡无光
His life would be empty without you!
对不起我自由发挥了一下 有感而发
I'm sorry I'm going off script. It just felt right.
没事
Oh. Good. Oh.
-太迟了 -不 这样好了
- T-too late. - No, you know what?
把你的手机给他
Give him your cellphone.
我去追海伦 然后把我的手机给她
I'll chase Helen down and give her my phone.
这样他们就可以好好谈谈了
They can hash it out.
你是 你是认真的吗
Are you -- are you serious?
没错 珍珠都没这么真
Yes, I'm serious as a heart attack.
你老是这样
You always do this.
我们连自己办的派对都要迟到了
Now we're gonna be late to our own party.
别叫了
Stop shouting.
严格来讲 我没有在
Well, technically, I wasn't really --
你好 喂 西摩·巴茨在吗[音同"多点屁屁"]
Uh, yes, hello. Is Seymour Butts there?
我从来没打过恶作剧电话
I'd never made a prank call...
没试过把好几种汽水兑到一起
never mixed different sodas together
尝尝是什么味
to see what they'd taste like.
所以我知道我必须
So I knew I had to make the most
充分利用一下我所剩不多的童年了
of what little childhood I had left.
不是拉茨 我要找巴茨[与"屁屁"同音]
Not "Lutts". I'm looking for Butts.
是的 我要找巴茨[与"屁屁"同音]
Yes, I'm trying to get ahold of Butts.
很好笑 我没时间跟你犯傻
Very funny. I don't have time for this foolishness.
也许你放东西应该更有条理
Maybe if you had a system for where you leave things.
我当然有条理
I have a system.
我把东西放下 然后再记住我放哪了
I put down things, then I remember where I put them.
比如说 你要是能把钥匙
And that would be preferable
放在这个长得像把大钥匙的
to, say, putting them on the key holder
钥匙架上就更好了
which just happens to look like a large key.
别再叫唤了
Stop screaming!
你在干吗
What are you doing?
找回逝去的童年
Turning back the clock.
真恶心
Disgusting!
不许说我 你又没结过婚
Don't judge me. You've never been married.
这件事从没发生过
This never happened.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
好样的 老伙计
That's a good man.
男孩 我是个男孩
Boy. I'm a boy!
你还好吧 没事吧
You all right? You okay?
还用问吗
W-why do you ask?
好的 我想这是找你的
Oh. Okay. Well, I think this is for you.
我 我不知道该跟他说什么
I-I don't know what to say to him.
你就敞开心扉然后听他说就好了 海伦
Just open your heart and listen, Helen.
好吧
Okay.
喂
Hello?
我把你的电话弄掉了
I dropped your phone.
我就在这眼睁睁地看着呢
I was here when it happened.
好了 没事的 我们就
Okay. It's all right. We'll just...
我做不到 我做不到
I can't. I-I just can't.
海伦 你要勇于尝试 我曾经
Helen, you have to try. I once almost let my own fears
差点被恐惧占据而放弃了一段感情
stop me from embarking on a relationship,
从而错过了我生命中的挚爱
and I would have lost the love of my life.
-海伦 -唐纳德
- Helen! - Donald!
-小卡 -坚持住 抓紧了 海伦
- Cam... - Hang on. Hang on, Helen!
我马上抱你下去
I'll have you down in a jiffy!
抓紧 别掐我
Hold on tight! Ow. Nails.
-海伦 别掐 别掐 -海伦
- Helen. Nails. Nails. Nails. - Helen.
海伦 求你再给我一次机会
Helen, please just give me a chance.
给他一个机会吧
Give him a chance!!
她现在就在这儿
She's right here.
小卡快点 我们没时间了
Cam, come on. We're running out of time.
谁说没时间了 瞎操心
We're running out of time? Sensitive.
接受他吧
Go to him.
真感谢你那么关心我们
Ohh, I-it's nice that you care so much about us.
没有爱的话我们什么都不是
Without love we're nothing.
但是他的老婆怎么办
But what about his wife?
很高兴认识你俩
It was a pleasure to meeting you both.
我知道了 卢克 你觉得他比较有趣
I get it, Luke. You think he's the fun one.
所以你才跟他一起
That's why you'd go with him.
什么
What?
你觉得你老爸比我有意思
You think your dad is more fun than I am.
-当然 -"当然"
- Definitely. - "Definitely."
老爸超级有趣
Dad's, like, crazy-fun.
-但是你很好人 -我就是个好人吗
- But you're nice. - I'm nice?!
现在不是了
Well, not now.
跟他说吧
Tell him.
-跟我说什么 -没事
- Tell me what? - Nothing.
姑娘们 我们管老爸的车叫什么
Hey, what do we call daddy's car, girls?
信任之蛋卷筒
The cone of trust.
信任之蛋卷筒 没错
The cone of trust. Exactamundo.
在这儿你们可以畅所欲言而不受批评
Where you can speak your mind with no judgment.
那么 是什么 关于男生吗
So, what is it? Boys?
你们的身体变化吗 还是排卵
Your bodies are changing? Eggs?
不 不
No! No.
我们只是想也许
We were just thinking that maybe...
如果你能接受的话
...if -- if you're open to it --
爸 我们爱你 但是我们今年真的
Dad, we love you, but we do not want
不想去家庭夏令营了
to go to family camp this year.
-爸 你生气了吗 -没有
- Dad? Are you upset? - Nope.
那这抽泣声是怎么回事
Then what was that sniff?
抽泣 什么抽泣 我 我
Sniff? What sniff? I'm -- I'm, uh --
我其实是如释重负
I'm actually relieved.
我一直在担心有一天
The day that I've been dreading,
你们最终长大了 不再需要我
uh, the day when you two finally outgrow me,
这天终于到来了
has finally arrived,
而我淡定得很
and I'm handling it really well.
-老爸 你在哭吗 -没有
- Dad, are you crying? - Nope.
-你确定你没事吗 -没事
- Are you sure you're okay? - Yep.
我的天哪 他哭了
Oh, my god. He is crying.
我以前从来没见咱爸哭过
I've never seen dad cry before.
但是 老爸 要是你哭的话 我也要哭了
But, dad, if you cry, then I'll cry!
我没哭
I'm not crying.
我们把老爸弄哭了
We made our daddy cry!
你叫我爸爸吗
You called me daddy?
因为你就是我们老爸
Because you are our daddy!
我永远是你们的爸爸
I'll always be your daddy!
别哭啊妈
Don't cry, mom.
我没哭
I am not crying.
我告诉你一个秘密 卢克
Let me fill you in on a little secret, Luke.
我刚跟你爸认识的时候 也很风趣
When I met your dad, I was fun, too.
但是后来我不得不放弃
But I had to give all that up,
因为你们不能有一对风趣的爸妈
because you can't have two fun parents.
那样就不可收拾了
That's a carnival.
你记得那个叫利亚姆的小孩吗 就是穿着睡衣上学
You know that kid Liam who wears pajama pants to school
然后用一百美元买东西的那个
and pays for things with a $100 bill?
他就有一对有趣的父母 记住我的话
Two fun parents. Mark my words.
啊 我的天
Oh, my god! Ohh!
老妈 你也很有趣
You're fun, too, mom.
我刚才说我要跟老爸一起
I just said I'd go with dad
是因为我觉得 他更需要我
because I think he'd need me more.
怎么我在这到处找 而你却干坐着
How come I do all the looking and you do all the sitting?
因为都是你弄丢的
'Cause you do all the losing.
你再唠叨 我就让你每天
Oh, and you're this close
都睡后院的帐篷
of doing all the sleeping in a tent in the backyard!
你翻过你的包了吗
Did you check your purse?
当然了
Yes, of course!
这包很大 你最好再检查一遍
It's a big purse. You might want to look again.
好吧 我检查 您老坐着
Okay. I check. You rest.
不在里面
No. There's nothing.
你确定
You're sure?
是的 我都看了两遍了
Yes. I've looked twice now.
-什么都没有 -好吧
- There's nothing. - Okay.
那你最好帮我们叫辆出租车
Then you better call us a cab!
曼尼 曼尼
Manny! Manny?
怎么回事 这东西哪来的
What the hell? Where'd that thing come from?
两年前的圣诞节 从来没从盒子里拿出来过
Christmas. Two years ago. Never took it out of the box.
我当时想"谁会喜欢这个呢"
"Who would enjoy that?" I thought.
答案就是 小朋友
A kid, that's who.
快点 我们要去你的派对了
Well, come on. We've got your party.
何必呢 你说的对 我生来就十六岁
What's the point? You were right. I-I was born 16.
我没有童年
I've lost my childhood.
你为什么让我再翻一遍包包 杰
Why did you want me to look again in my purse, Jay, huh?
是不是你把钥匙放进去的
Is it because you put the keys in there?
我没有 怎么 你找到钥匙了吗
No. Why, did you find it?
没错 那是因为是你把钥匙放进去的
Yes, I found them because you put the keys in there!
曼尼 你他奶奶的在那干什么呢
Manny, what the hell are you doing there?
他想取消派对 因为他错过了童年
He wants to cancel his party because he missed his childhood
这个派对我重新安排了三次
The party that I have rescheduled three times,
换了两次餐厅
changed the restaurant twice
就为了全家能聚在一起 你现在说不去了
so that the whole family could be together?!
我表示抱歉
Please send my regrets.
现在可以给我点私人空间了吧
Now, if I could have a little privacy...
私人空间
Privacy?! Esto es lo que me faltaba a me.
私人空间吗
Privacy?! En esta casa?
下面那个是滑板吗
Is that a skateboard down there?
这是我今天失去的第二件东西
The second thing that slipped right out from under me today.
好了 快出来吧
Okay, time to get out.
第一个是我的童年
The first was my childhood.
我知道了
I get it!
我真讨厌固执的人
I am so sick of stubborn men!
你 你表现的就像个
You, you act like a little boy
不承认自己犯了错的小屁孩
That doesn't want to accept that he's wrong.
而你就像一个自怨自艾的老头子
And you like a sad old man that doesn't want to be happy!
老娘受够了
That's it!
-你会射中我的 -得了吧 曼尼
- You could have shot me! - Come on, Manny.
要是我想 我可以用这个打掉你的扣子
I could've unbuttoned your shirt if I wanted to.
要么速度滚上来 要么跟着这岛一起沉没
Now come here, or sink!
我会在车上带着这把枪的
And I'm taking this with me in the car.
我们走吧
Vamonos.
我认得你这表情 米奇尔
I know that face, Mitchell.
好吧 我们要赶路呢
Okay, a-and we're walking.
你这表情是说你对了 而我错了
It means you were right and I was wrong
就因为我要帮助那俩人
for trying to help two people.
-帮那对偷情的人吗 -我没话讲
- Adulterers? - Fair enough.
说实话 他们是我见过最老的偷情者了
A-actually, the most adult adulterers ever.
但我的初衷是好的
But my impulse was still right.
-天呐 又来了 - 生活就是
- Oh, god. Here we go. - Life is about being --
怎么 我就是要说
Yes. You know what? Here we do go.
生活就是要跟着感觉走
It's about being spontaneous.
做自己想做的事情
It's about throwing yourself into something,
而不是每晚都在公司工作加班
not working long hours every night at the office.
你就像是生活在自己的...
It's like you're living your l--
-神马情况 -不知道
- What is this? - I don't know.
打扰一下 警官 这是神马情况
Excuse me, constable, what -- what is going on?
我知道了 是快闪族 快闪族
Oh, it's a flash mob! It's a flash mob!
还记得吗 我们一起在视频网上看过
Ooh! We saw it on Youtube. Remember?
许多人们聚在一起跳舞
People get together and choreograph big dance numbers!
我们还是快走吧 这有点怪异
We should go. T-this is kind of weird.
不要 这很有趣 米奇尔
No, this is joyful, Mitchell.
你应该...
You, of all people, should --
小卡说的对 我是有点死板
Cam's right. I can be a little rigid.
所以有一天当会计部的查德
So when Chad from accounting,
一个我一直以为是男同
who I always thought was gay
但其实却不是的人
but apparently is not,
问我要不要参加这次的快闪族活动
Um, told me about this flash mob,
我说 当然愿意
I thought, "Hells yes".
我们每礼拜有好几天在下班后练舞
Uh, we've been practicing after work a couple of nights a week.
我们付出了很多
And it's -- it's been a big commitment,
但这太值了
but it's totally worth it.
这次的舞蹈是我对小卡的一次爱的表白
This dance is my love letter to Cam.
好了 这就是我一直催你的原因
Okay, so, this is why I was rushing you around.
怎么样 有没有改变你对我的看法
Huh? What do you think of me now?
你怎么能这样对我 米奇尔
How could you, Mitchell?
怎么了 卡梅隆
What? Cameron.
-卡梅隆 -别烦我 唐纳德
- Cameron. - Not now. Donald!
你也有搞笑的时候
You do fun stuff.
你曾放过一片薯片在我的三明治里
You put that potato chip in my sandwich.
咔嚓一声 吓了我一跳
That was a crunchy surprise.
那是你爸的主意 家里的笑料都是他的主意
Nope, that was your dad. Everything fun is your dad.
圣再诞节 意大利口音之夜
Second Christmas, Italian-accent night...
还有这次比赛
this race.
我们能赢这次比赛的 你挑的路近多了
Which we could've won. Your way is way faster.
那是当然啊
It is, isn't it?
坐稳了 卢克
Buckle up, Luke.
今天你将有一对搞笑的父母
Today you have two fun parents.
老妈加油 我相信你
Come on, mom. You can do it.
那是当然
That's right I can.
说实话吧 杰
Tell me the truth, Jay.
是不是你把钥匙放在我包里的
Did you put the key in my bag?
不是
No.
我不会生气
I won't be mad.
为了证明我的观点 我有可能
In order to prove a point, I may have --
我就知道
I knew it!
我怎么会给你买这么大一块表
Why did I get you such a big watch?!
为什么 杰 你到底想证明什么
Why, Jay?! What point did you have to prove?!
我想让你变得有条理
I'm trying to teach you to be organized.
你太散漫了 歌洛莉亚
Your mind is scattered, Gloria.
看看待会谁比较散
Your mind is gonna be scattered.
曼尼 把枪拿来
Manny, hand me the gun!
谢谢你献舞给我
I appreciate the gesture,
我也觉得我这个态度不太好
and I'm not proud of how I'm feeling right now,
可问题是 你对我不忠
but the fact is, you cheated on me.
我这算哪门子不忠
In what way did I cheat on you?
你瞒着我排练舞蹈
You cheated on me with choreography,
这是最严重的不忠
and that is the worst kind.
这真的不算
Well, it really isn't.
你居然不带我 自己去跳舞 米奇尔
You danced without me, Mitchell!
早知道去年是我最后一次野营
If I'd known it was my last summer there,
我就去竞争Pippin游戏社团的领导
I'd have gone for the lead in "Pippin."
老爸 看前面 老妈正朝我们开过来
Dad, look up ahead. Coming at us. There's mom!
打败他
Beat her!
我认为他现在没心情比赛
I don't think he's in the mood for that right now.
够了 不行
Hold on. No.
现在最需要赢得胜利的人 就是你
If ever a man needed a win, it's this man.
你觉得呢 老爸
What do you say, dad?
好的 为了家庭野营
Okay. This one's for family camp.
冲 冲 冲 冲 冲 冲 冲 冲
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
-这感觉太刺激了 -我爱你
- This is so inappropriate! - I love you!
冲 冲 冲 冲 冲 冲 冲 冲
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
妈妈 小心
Mom, look out!
小心 小卡
Cam!
有人受伤吗
Anybody hurt?
我
I am.
我今天本来郁闷得都不想来了
I was almost too depressed to come today.
我发现我虚度了我的童年
I realized I let my childhood slip away.
看看卢克
Look at Luke there...
用三个吸管连成一根长的
making one big straw out of three.
保持童心吧 卢克
Never change, Luke.
我真的以为现在挽回童年已经太迟了
I really thought it was too late for me.
但看到你们都这么大了还一个个耍孩子气
But watching all you acting like children,
我恍然大悟 我还有大把时间当小孩呢
it hit me -- I've got plenty of time left to be a kid.
总而言之 祝我生日快乐
Anyway, happy birthday to me.
生日快乐 曼尼
Happy birthday, Manny.
我太小孩子气了
I have been a child.
抱歉我藏了你的钥匙
I'm sorry I hid the keys.
很抱歉我射沉了那座小岛
I'm sorry I shoot the island.
我们回家的路上再比一次
We're totally racing home.
我可比你快多了
I'm way ahead of you.
一向如此
As usual.
天气预报说本周末会下雨
They say it's going to be a rainy weekend.
天气预报啥时候准过
They don't know.
可是我准 我的膝盖都响了一个早上了
I do. My knee's been singing all morning.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
我的妈呀
Mother of g --
把钥匙放下 然后走开
Put them down and walk away.
我跟你说 歌洛莉亚
You know, Gloria --